# Cristian Nieto



cristianandresnieto@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/cristian-nieto-14209366



+573147909276



https://crisnietodev.vercel.app/

# **Summary**

I am a Fullstack engineer with +10 years of experience habituated to work on all-sizes companies and all types of business. My experience is in the back-end with Java and NodeJS, and in the front-end with React, Vue, and ReactNative . work for a wide variety of clients and projects have enhanced my engineering skills which I will put into each coming project that I will involved in.

# **Experience**

## Contract Developer

intive

May 2022 - Present (1 year 5 months)

Work in the migration from domains to micro-services architecture project. I work migrating functions to micro-services with NodeJS, KOA and open-api 3.0.

My job in this project as part of the Vector development team is participating in daily meetings, grooming session and different technical meetings. Work in the planned tickets for the sprint, do code reviews and help team mates with technical doubts.

Tech stack used

- NodeJS
- ES6
- KoaJS
- PostgreSQL
- OpenAPI

# Contract Developer

intive

May 2022 - Oct 2022 (6 months)

Worked on the project of migrating the knot catalog to Contentful. had to build some jobs with NodeJS and NestJS that connect to the legacy catalog and then migrate the items to Contentful using Contentful GraphQL Content API I worked on the knot webpage as well which is developed with React my work was mainly in the Catalog page getting the items from Contentful and listed them in the webpage.

My job in this project as part of the Vector development team is participating in daily meetings, grooming session and different technical meetings. Work in the planned tickets for the sprint, do code reviews and help team mates with technical doubts.

Tech stack used

- NodeJS
- ReactJS
- TypeScript
- NextJS

- Contentful

### deviget Contract Developer

#### Deviget LLC

Nov 2021 - May 2022 (7 months)

React developer working with two clients based in Silicon Valley within both clients I work developing totally reusable and accessible React components which are connected to contentful CMS.

Here we integrate CMS to React 16 using hooks and GraphQL so each component is represented based on the information received from the CMS gotten with GraphQL

My main duties here are participating in daily stand-up meetings, grooming sessions and technical meetings, based on the backlog working on the tickets prioritized for the PM when I finish developing the ticket and I get all the approvals from the repo owners and mates and must merge my PR validating that all the checks passed and notified to the team the deployment status. I have to be pending if there are some bugs open too and check whether a fix is needed or it is a misconfiguration from the editors/ users.

#### Tech stack used

- React (Functional components and hooks)
- GraphQL
- Styled components
- Chakra UI
- Storybook
- React testing library

Web page built using components created https://www.goodrx.com/



### 🎇 Senior Software Engineer

#### Avantica

Nov 2020 - Oct 2021 (1 year)

I work in each stage of the software development process, starting with the design until testing and deployment. I work specifically with Cision client a client from USA that helps all its clients to analyze their brand in different mediums of communication and social media for making better decisions in the market.

Cision offers its clients a web application where they can use Cision's own query system where users can find articles and social media content and see what people are talking about them analyze information and create dashboards to analyze results. I worked in a team where we created and improved each component used within the web app using tech stack listed below.

My main functions are developing new features that Cision offers to its clients. I have to participate in daily meetings, and grooming sessions then I develop tickets prioritized by the PM. Work in a 4 developers team where each one of us must review tickets from the other ones after a ticket is approved I must merge it and check the deployment process using Jenkins.

#### Tech stack used

- React

- ES6
- TypeScript
- Redux
- Groovy
- MySql
- Storybook



## doffti Full Stack Developer

### Dafiti Group LATAM

Mar 2020 - Nov 2020 (9 months)

I work helping different software projects in Dafiti Latam developing software in different technologies like Node JS, and Java I worked on different projects with them as the PWA and some internal logistics applications where they handle their hubs and run algorithms to package and handle the logistic to fulfill shipment time to their clients.

Dafiti is one of the biggest fashion markets places in LATAM located in Colombia, Argentina, Chile, and Brasil. Dafiti uses different digital platforms to sell its products like web page, PWA, and mobile application.

I worked with Dafiti in the PWA project which is the web store that the clients use to buy using mobile devices and participate in projects like migrating the whole design of the store using the new design defined for the design team I worked as well on the redesign of the payment flow on the PWA

Tech stack used

- Node JS
- React (Class components and functional components)
- Redux
- Java
- Jest
- React testing library



### **Development Specialist**

#### Branch

Jan 2020 - Present (3 years 9 months)

Entrepreneurship - Here I am developing my own idea of building an application that allows clients to handle history of their own vehicles (car/motorbike) each time that they go to visit the automobile repair shop all the changes made to the vehicle keep registered.

To achieve it I created three applications the first one is the backend which was built using NodeJS with Express and typescript following micro-services architecture, the second one is the web application which is used at the vehicle repair shop totally adapted to mobile devices or tablets was built using Vue JS with ES6 (migrating it now to typescript), the third one is the mobile application which is used for the end-user where they can communicate through our own chat with the shop and check the whole repairing process and handle the history of its own vehicle this app was built using React Native with ES6.



## **Senior Software Engineer Consulting**

#### 4smart

Mar 2019 - Dec 2019 (10 months)

I was the architect and one of the main developers of a back-end software solution built with NodeJS that handles the communication of Daviplata's customers. The application exposes some API to receive messages from the consumer (Web App or Mobile App) and connects them to IBM Watson Assistant API where we developed our chatbot, the software handle IBM Watson outcome and sends them back to the clients. The clients connect through daviplata App (IOS, Android). We did a web page embedded in Daviplata App The web page use WebSocket (Socket IO) to connect to our Application. I developed a Web Application in Vue JS to manage the ChatBot to train it and see the current efectiveness of the Bot and improved it.

### Leader innovation Tech

Sistemcobro S.A.S

Jan 2018 - Mar 2019 (1 year 3 months)

I worked on a investigation project for knowing different IBM Watson APIs its different benefits and usability. I did an application in NodeJS that it connect the different IBM Watson APIs. The application was developed in Vue JS for the Front End and NodeJS (Express) in the back end. The application is deploy IBM Cloud and each change is updated using CI/CD with GitLab.

# Head of Information Technology

Sistemcobro S.A.S

Mar 2017 - Dec 2017 (10 months)

Project Management of Data Warehousing, analysis and design of ETL components, design and architecture of the DWH according to the business need and implementation of OLAP cubes with Analysis Services, also everything that has to do with the administration of the databases of the Company on Sql server engine versions 2008, 2012 and 2016

# Software Engineering Team Lead

Sistemcobro S.A.S

Mar 2016 - Mar 2017 (1 year 1 month)

Design, define and implement software solutions under the Java JEE architecture, implement efficient and sustainable solutions under different architectural design patterns, using good software development practices. Survey of requirements, design of UML diagrams of software solutions. Leadership capacity and internal and external management that allowed the success of the different projects that I direct. Design of data models for process automation of massive information loading through ETL.



#### Software Analyst

Sistemcobro SA

Oct 2013 - Mar 2016 (2 years 6 months)

Develop software solutions in the programming language JAVA j2ee, creation of SOAP and REST web services, administration and configuration of glassfish application servers under linux centos

environment, administration and configuration of BD SQL Server 2008 and 2012, massive data management through of ETL with Talend and visualization of information with Tableau

# Junior Java Developer

Stefanini Brasil

Oct 2012 - Oct 2013 (1 year 1 month)

Develop web applications under the JAVA JEE language, using components such as JPA, EJB 2 and EJB 3, creation of SOAP web clients and services on JBOSS servers and Oracle database 11 g, unit tests, analysis and implementation of use cases, documentation of software solutions under the SCRUM methodology

# Java Web Developer

J3 SOLUTIONS SAS

Oct 2011 - Oct 2012 (1 year 1 month)

Develop web applications under the programming language JAVA with JEE and J2EE technology, handling frameworks such as Spring, hibernate and JSF, administration and configuration of application servers in windows and Linux environments, administration and configuration of SQL Server 2008 database servers, analysis and documentation of use cases according to the end user's requests.

#### **Education**

Corporación Universitaria Minuto de Dios

Ingeniería, Ingeniería de sistemas 2009 - 2016

Corporación Universitaria Minuto de Dios

Tecnologo en Informatica, Information Technology 2009 - 2013

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

SOA Professional - Arcitura Education Inc. 109872

SOA Architect - Arcitura Education Inc.
109872

SEI - Certified PSP Developer - Software Engineering Institute | Carnegie Mellon University
1736548

## Data Science Foundations - Level 1 - IBM

# Python for Data Science - IBM

# **Skills**

Java • Node.js • ETL • Arquitectura orientada a servicios (SOA) • Administración de bases de datos • Procesamiento de grandes volúmenes de datos • Servicios web • React.js • Jest • React Native